Preliminary Inventory to the Arthur Leroy Carson Collection, 1921-1979
Hoover Institution Archives
Arthur Leroy Carson Collection,
1921-1979
78098
Carson, Arthur Leroy, 1895-
39 manuscript boxes (16.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, notes, reports, clippings and other printed matter, relating to education in the Philippines; political, social, economic, and religious conditions in the Philippines; and educational and missionary activities elsewhere in Asia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Silliman University.; Trinity College of Quezon City.; Education.; Education--Asia.; Education--Philippines.; Missions--Asia.; Missions--Philippines.; Universities and colleges--Philippines.; Asia.; Philippines.; Missionaries.
Container List
- Carson, Arthur L., "A Trip to Linchow (1921)" (Box 1.)
- Carson, Edith S., "Philippine Adventure"
- Notes on higher education (P.I.)
- Medicine and health (P.I.)
- Peace Corps
- Asia Foundation
- Puericulture Center (P.I.)
- Christian Institute on Special Ethnic Communities (P.I.)
- Reviews of books (P.I.)
- Language (P.I.)
- Adult education bibliography
- Adult education literacy (P.I.)
- Propaganda
- Adult education extension
- Surveys of communities (P.I.)
- Adult education (Silliman University)
- Adult education audio-visual (P.I.)
- Adult education pre-war (P.I.)
- Adult education (Silliman University)
- Carson, Arthur L., "Education in the Republic of the Philippines" (Box 2.)
- "Survey of Mission and Church Education in Pakistan"
- War Control Planners, Inc.
- Labor (P.I.)
- Rural improvement
- Philippine Rural Reconstruction Movement
- Cooperatives (P.I.)
- Huks
- Land reform (P.I.)
- Rural improvement
- Anthropology (P.I.) (Box 3.)
- Trinity College of Quezon City programs
- Baguio
- Washington, D.C., Service in, 1944-1945
- Ecumenical movement, 1961-1963
- Rotz, H. Welton
- Correspondence, 1935-1954
- Association for Asian Studies, Annual meeting, 1969
- Coemar Library reports
- Economics and business (P.I.)
- Chinese in the Philippines
- Geography (P.I.)
- History (P.I.)
- Return visit to Silliman University, 1974 (Box 4.)
- Silliman University
- Philippines (miscellaneous clippings)
- Endicott, N.Y., First Presbyterian Church
- Council on Christian Higher Education in Asia
- Christian University
- Study Fellowship
- Church and mission
- New society (P.I.)
- Marcos, Ferdinand
- Amnesty International report on P.I.
- Martial law (P.I.)
- Barangay organization (P.I.)
- Maps (P.I.)
- Philippine Studies Newsletter
- Speeches and articles by A. L. Carson, 1942-1956 (Box 5.)
- Trinity College of Quezon City
- Philippine Episcopal Church
- Episcopal Church in the U.S.A.
- Association of Episcopal College newsletters
- Association of Episcopal Colleges and Trinity College of Quezon City
- Trinity College presidential papers, 1964-1967
- Trinity College correspondence
- Social problems and agencies (P.I.) (Box 6.)
- Alcoholism
- Culture (P.I.)
- Community development (P.I.)
- Agency for International Development
- Macutay, Faustino S., and Valentin G. Cedillo, "An Approach to Community Development in a Cultural Minority Setting"
- Presbyterian schools and colleges
- Education (P.I.)
- Education
- Plant Science Congress, Cornell University, 1926
- Education (P.I.) - Clippings, 1962-1967
- Denmark
- Church World Service
- Educational institutions (P.I.) (Box 7.)
- Manila City University
- Dansalan Junior College
- Maasin Institute (College)
- Notre Dame Educational Association
- Southern Christian College (P.I.), 1967
- Colleges and universities, Public (P.I.)
- Commission on Christian Education (P.I.)
- Accreditation (P.I.)
- Inter-university conferences (P.I.), 1939-1960
- Cooperation - Consortia (P.I. education), 1964-1966
- Clemente, Fred Al, II
- Student activists (P.I.), 1969
- Students (P.I.)
- Teachers (P.I.)
- Silliman University - Founders Day
- Silliman University publications
- Silliman University songs
- Plants, animals and products (P.I.)
- Politics (P.I.), 1975-1976
- "My Unforgettable Experience" newspaper column (P.I.)
- Humor (P.I.)
- Sweepstakes (P.I.)
- Morals and crime (P.I.)
- Transportation (P.I.)
- Marriage and the home (Box 8.)
- Miscellaneous and general
- Correspondence, Professional
- Higher education (P.I.) - Correspondence, 1952-1974
- Secondary education (P.I.)
- Private schools (P.I.) - Finances, 1970
- Private school enrollment (P.I.)
- Education
- National College Entrance Examinations
- Fund for Assistance to Private Education
- Administration (P.I. education), 1960-1966
- Schools (P.I.) - Clippings
- American teachers in the Philippines, 1938-1966
- Secularism (Box 9.)
- Cooperatives, 1965-1967
- Communism
- Rizal, Jose
- Educational personages (P.I.)
- Persons (P.I.)
- Orata, Pedro
- Philippine Society for Curriculum Development
- Macapagal, Diosdado
- Mott, John R.
- Gonzalez, Bienvenido M., Resignation of
- Hart, Donn V.
- MacArthur, Douglas
- Correspondence and miscellany
- Miscellany
- War damage (P.I.), 1945-1948 (Box 10.)
- Religion (P.I.) - Clippings
- Association of Christian Schools and Colleges (P.I.)
- Carson, A. L., The Story of Philippine Education - Correspondence regarding, 1960-1977
- Carson, A. L., The Story of Philippine Education - Sources for, 1970-1978
- Politics (P.I.)
- Population (P.I.)
- Philippine - U.S. relations
- Fulbright program (P.I.)
- Government agencies (P.I.)
- Science (P.I.), 1958-1960
- Japan
- Venezuela
- Freedom House
- Forman, James, and white and black activists (U.S.), 1969 (Box 11.)
- Vietnam War Moratorium (U.S.), 1969
- Nixon, Richard M., 1964-1975
- Roman Catholics (P.I.)
- Muslims (P.I.)
- National Council of Churches in the Philippines
- Deats, Richard, "Nationalism and the Churches in the Philippines"
- Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions, 1953-1963
- Philippine Independent Church
- War claims (P.I.), 1951-1965
- Community Council (P.I.) (Box 12.)
- Adult education
- Book lists
- Community Council (P.I.)
- "Survey Report on Theological Education in the Philippines"
- Wicke, Myron F., "Methodist Schools and Colleges in the Philippine Islands"
- Baguio Religious Acculturation Conference, 1958
- Silliman, Robert B., comp., "Religious Beliefs and Life at the Beginning of the Spanish Regime in the Philippines"
- Higher education (P.I.), 1962
- Vietnam
- Community school (P.I.) (Box 13.)
- Aguilar, Jose
- Malabo community schools
- Carson, A. L., chapel talks, Tunghai University, 1956
- United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia - Printed matter
- United Board, 1953-1958
- United Board, 1962-1969
- United Board, 1970-1978
- Notes
- Rural community development (P.I.)
- Rural community Development Program (Silliman University)
- Community education (P.I.)
- Community development (P.I.)
- Community Council relief (P.I.)
- Community Council - Minutes of meetings (P.I.)
- Community education (P.I.)
- Rural life (Box 14.)
- Cooperatives (Silliman University)
- Agricultural economics (Silliman University)
- Rural church
- Rural education
- Rural health
- Rural life
- "Education" (P.I.), 1967
- Miscellaneous printed matter
- Carson, Edith - Mementos and papers
- Carson, Edith - Letters and memorial service
- Carson, Edith, "A Community Education Program"
- Carson, Edith, and Malabo Community Center
- Community school (P.I.)
- Villalino, Ignacio A., "A Study of the Effects of the Malabo Community Center upon the Rural People"
- National Conference on Education, Baguio, 1964 (Box 15.)
- Institute for Church-Related Administrators, United Church of Christ in the Philippines, 1966
- Cooperating Council of Private Educational Associations
- Philippine Association of Colleges and Universities
- Catholic Educational Association of the Philippines
- Association of Christian Colleges and Universities (P.I.)
- Philosophy of education (P.I.)
- Educational manpower (P.I.)
- Education
- Philippine Bureau of Private Schools - Statistical reports
- Barrio high schools and Pangasinan visit
- Student problems (P.I.)
- Mindanao State University, 1937
- School finances (P.I.)
- Miscellany
- Mimeographed material (Box 16-18.)
- Government documents (published) (Box 18-20.)
- Reports of private organizations, university catalogs, etc. (published) (Box 20-26.)
- Pamphlets, brochures, etc. (published) (Box 26-27.)
- Printed matter (Box 28-34.)
- Speeches and writings by Arthur L. Carson (Box 35.)
- Trinity College News, 1964-1966
- Silliman University history
- Silliman University extension
- Personal letters
- Edith Scott Carson letters, 1939-1967
- Edith Scott Carson - Life and work
- Mid-Atlantic Regional Association for Asian Studies
- Association for Asian Studies - Philippine Study Council, 1973-1977
- Clippings on the Philippines
- Philippine adventure
- American Universities Field Staff reports
- Visit to Silliman University (Box 36.)
- Silliman University history
- War-time correspondence and clippings
- Reports on selection of President of Silliman University
- Minutes of meetings
- Trinity College (Quezon City) and Episcopal Church Foundation
- Miscellany
- Mission publications
- Gambling
- American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1973-1979
- Correspondence, 1938-1979
- Correspondence with Silliman University
- Correspondence with Silliman alumni
- Correspondence with Asia Foundation, 1967-1975
- Speeches and writings by Arthur L. Carson
- Printed matter (Box 37.)
- Publications of various Philippine educational institutions (Box 38.)
- Publications of Silliman University
- Reports of the Philippine Board of National Education and Bureau of Private Schools (Box 39.)
- Barrio High School material
- Miscellaneous printed matter
- Carson, Erna, "The Orient Experience"